William Neil Smith papers, 1829-1975 (Bulk 1944-1970)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series V: Research Files, 1890-1975
  - Census and Genealogy
    - Census data -- Observation and notes -- Males born prior to January 1930. 1950 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Census data -- Birth and death records, 1948-1960; families; records of descendants; Kinship linguistic records [on index cards]. 1948-1960 (Box 11)
    - Census data -- All Seris living December 31, 1947, or born after that date (includes Key to Cross-Index File) [on index cards]. 1947 (Box 12)
    - Census data, 1890-1947 [on index cards]. 1890-1947 (Box 13)
  - Sea Turtle Figurine Study
    - Figurines: Correspondence. 1954-1970 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with Carl L. Hubbs, Scripps Institute. 1963-1964 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Carl Schuster. 1963-1970 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous notes, sketches, references. ca. 1965 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Manuscript draft with annotations by Bernard Fontana. 1966-1968 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Manuscript draft. 1967 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Abstract of paper presented at American Association for Advancement of Science Annual Meeting. 1967 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Notes and observations, questions. 1967-1969 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Kunkaak Culture - Tiburon Island, manuscript draft with comments by Charles Di Peso, Director, Amerind Foundation. 1969 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Notes - Journal articles. ca. 1960s (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Photographs of types I-IV, caches, brands and other miscellaneous figurine photographs, by Carl Schuster. ca. 1960s (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Figurines: Types and geographic ranges. 1963 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Types -- Smith classification. ca. 1960s (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Photographs from other sites, museum. 1967 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Specimens from Arizona State Museum -- Photographs. ca. 1960s (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Specimens from Mexico, Collection of the University of Pennsylvania Museum -- Photographs. ca. 1960s (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Figurines and "Estrellas" - Photographs by Carl Schuster. ca. 1960s (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Photographs by Carl Schuster, in package sent to Bernard Fontana, Arizona State Museum. ca. 1960s (Box 15, Folder 7-8)
    - Figurines: Photographs by Carl Schuster. ca. 1960s (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
    - Miscellaneous photographs. ca. 1960s (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Cruciform object study (prehistoric). 1960s (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Film Projects
    - Seri film -- Viking fund grant. 1951-1952 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Mickey Mouse Club Television Program, "Seri Children's Activities," ("Peoples and Places in the World," T.V., spring 1955). 1955 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Clippings. 1955 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Disney Studios. 1955-1956 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Seri film -- Plan and organization used in shooting film, Tiburon Island, 1950-1954. ca. 1960 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Seri film -- Map data, organization of titles, introduction and plan for organization of reels I and II. ca. 1960 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Seri film -- Notes and data -- Cutting records, footage records. July-September 1960 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Seri film -- Notes -- Sequence organization. 1960 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Seri film - Notes on grants, correspondence, other film projects. 1960-1962 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Seri film -- Data on University of Arizona project. 1961 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Introduction to Accompany the Moving Picture "The Seri Indians of Tiburon Island," by W. N. Smith (text for film). 1966 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence -- Patos Island film. 1966-1969 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Four Seasonal Coverage of the Ecological Aspects of Survival in a Sub-marginal Marine-Desert Environment, by W. N. Smith (film notes). 1968 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Subject Files
    - Seri subject files
      - Balsa boats. 1955 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Band distribution -- Notes and maps. 1956 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Basketry. 1952 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Bibliography. (Box 18, Folder 4-8)
      - Birth control practices. (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Blanket drive. 1948 (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - Boat project (to raise funds for purchase of lumber to make boat for Montano Family). 1950 (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - Camps -- Household composition. 1949-1953 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Clippings. 1950-1956 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Clippings. 1952-1975 (Box 19, Folder 3-4)
      - Clippings -- Seri political movement. 1955-1956 (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Clippings -- Native American and other miscellaneous. 1943-1975 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Culture change. 1950-1960 (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Ethnography. 1949 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Ethnography (Tiburon Island). 1949 (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - Ethnography (Tiburon, San Esteban Islands, etc.). 1947-1952 (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - Exhibit -- Arizona State Museum. 1970-1971 (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - Exhibit in Harold Porter's window. 1951 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Exhibit -- Tucson Festival of the Arts. 1951 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Face paintings and miscellaneous drawings. 1946-1949 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Fishing cooperative, (original formation at Bahia Kino--1934--Lazero Cardenas--Cooperativa de la Tribu Seri--Vaguero was orignal head). 1949 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Fund/expenses. 1952 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - History -- Spanish period. 1600-1800 (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - History -- 19th century. 1800-1900 (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Historical records. 1900-1920 (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - Historical records. 1920-1930 (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Historical records. 1930-1940 (Box 20, Folder 10)
      - Historical records. 1940-1950 (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - Historical records. 1950- (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - Influenza vaccine for Seri. 1956 (Box 20, Folder 13)
      - Ironwood carvings. 1969 (Box 20, Folder 14)
      - Kinship. ca. 1950 (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - Language. 1947-1952 (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
      - Lecture: Heard Museum, Phoenix. January 15-16, 1948 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Heard Museum, Phoenix. January 26-27, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Heard Museum, Phoenix. February 7-8, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - Hermosillo, Sonora. February 16, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Kiwanis, Scottsdale, Arizona. March 24, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Santa Barbara Museum of Natural History. February 1949 (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - Lectures -- Miscellaneous records. 1944-1965 (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - Maps (annotated by W.N. Smith). 1944-1952 (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - Maps. 1947-1952 (Box 21, Folder 11-12)
      - Maps. ca. 1950 (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - Maps. ca. 1952 (Box 21, Folder 14)
      - Materials collected for Seri by W.N. Smith. 1947-1963 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Measles epidemic. Spring 1955 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous notes -- Seri lifeway. 1950s (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Notes on field methods. (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Preparations for trips to Seri country. 1947-1952 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Puberty ceremony songs. 1958 (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Puberty records. 1950-1955 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Quakers-American Friends Service Committee (A.F.S.C.). 1947-1954 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Quakers -- Notes/correspondence -- W.N. Smith. 1948-1953 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Quakers -- A.F.S.C. -- Norman Krekler letter (also L. Warren, J. Collins, and D. Spence). 1949-1951 (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - Quakers -- A.F.S.C. 1950 (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - Quakers -- A.F.S.C. project. 1950-1955 (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - Quakers -- A.F.S.C. project -- Sandoval-Scholl data. 1955-1956 (Box 22, Folder 13)
      - Quakers -- A.F.S.C. project. 1955-1961 (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - Religion. 1966 (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - Seri Fund records. 1953-1955 (Box 22, Folder 16)
      - Visit to Arizona. September-October 1948 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Visit to Arizona and California. 1950 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Visit to Tucson, northern Arizona. September-November 1951 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous subject files
      - American Anthropological Association. 1946 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - American Anthropological Association, 52nd annual meeting. 1953 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - American Ethnological Society Meeting, Tucson. 1953 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - American Folklore Society. ca. 1950 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - American Indian Ethnohistoric Conference, Tucson. 1965 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Congress of Mexican Historians, La Paz, Lower California. January-February 1952 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - IX Congreso Nacional de Sociologia, Hermosillo, Sonora. 1962 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Southern Arizona School for boys, Tucson. 1934-1960s (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Verde Valley School, Sedona, Arizona. 1948-1949 (Box 23, Folder 12)
- Series VI: Audio-Visual Media, 1922-1974
  - Photographs and Negatives
    - Miscellaneous photograph notes. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Scenes at "An-desh-ee-oh-tumm," basket making, bee cave. November 1947 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Arizona Daily Star article. (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Arizona State Museum Exhibit. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Bahia Kino area, Tiburon Island, Rancho Santa Cruz - photographs from Sonora Museum, Hermosillo. 1920s-1930s (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Bahia Kino: by Otis H. Chidester. 1935 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Bahia Kino: by Otis H. Chidester. 1936 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Bahia Kino, Punta de la Cruz: by Edward H. Davis. 1929 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Bahia Kino: by Edward H. Davis. 1939 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Bahia Kino: by Lynn Hodgson. April-May 1938 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Bahia Kino, including Kino Bay Club: by Monte Mansfield. 1929-1931 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Bahia Kino: by John Murphey. 1931 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Bahia Kino and Isla Alcatraz: by Tad Nichols. 1932-1933 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Bahia Kino: by Frank Putter. 1928-1929 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Bahia Kino: by Robert Scott. 1940 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Balsa Boat at Desemboque: by Luis Hammond. July 1954 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Basket collection of W. N. Smith (negatives). (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Basket collection of W. N. Smith, #1-100. (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Basket collection of W. N. Smith, #101-275. (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Basket collection of W. N. Smith, #276-300. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Basket making. 1947 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Basket making - photographs used in article by W. N. Smith in Kiva (Oct. 1959). 1947 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Basket manufacture at "Hactoe," Pozo Caracol, Tiburon Island [Amelia Montaño]. October 1947 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Boat purchased for Seri tribe, Guaymas, Sonora: by Beltran Photo. 1928 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Bow making from cats caw -- "Hactoe," Pozo Caracol, Tiburon Island [Jesus Cayetano, Joses Montano]; sketch map of "Hactoe." October 1947 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Camp at Ann-Kluh - "Boca del Infiernillo." 1947 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Camps, south shore, Tiburon Island: by Dr. John S. Garth, Hancock Expedition. March 1936 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Desemboque and Tiburon Island (Ach-Aach, Tecomate): by W.N. Smith. January and Summer 1946 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Desemboque. ca. 1947 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Desemboque: by Art Pollard. November 1947 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Face painting. (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Face paints - from Torote. 1947 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Field notebook photographs. 1946-1947 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Fire-making. ca. 1950 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Group photographs. (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Guaymas, Sonora: by Roberto Thompson. 1930 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Historic photographs. (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Hactoe "Pozo Caracol," hunting honey, scenes in camp at "Hactoe." October 1947 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Individual photographs. (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Mexican Sonoran ranch families -- 1. Girls at Las Pozas de San Ignazio, 2. Boys from La Gloria and Las Estrellas Ranches; Seri frontier, north of Desemboque (negatives). 1946 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Notes and description of 20 (4 x 5) Kodachromes, 38 (4 x 5) black and white prints - preparation for magazine article. 1953 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Montaño Family. 1947 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - With Montaño Family on east coast, Tiburon Island and at inland camps: by W. N. Smith (negatives). October-November 1947 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Montaño Family and other Seris camped at "Shoshonee Gweem-pluh" and later at "Ahnkluh," mouth of Infiernillo, Tiburon Island. October 1947 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Montaño Family - trail from Ast Hoen-nih-huh (Honieh) camp to "Shosh-nee Gweeum-pluh" Infiernillo mouth, Tiburon Island. October 1947 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Pottery making. (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Quaker-built school house inauguration, Desemboque, including students from University of Sonora, Hermosillo. Fall 1953 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Rancho Providencia, 3 miles east of Bahia Kino: by J.A. Ivey. 1922-1923 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - San Esteban Island: by Ike Russell. 1968 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Seri: by Jack M. Barrow. 1949 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Seri: by Gordon Gordon. ca. 1933-1934 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Seri: by Hugh Holub. (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Seri: by Franz Kurth. June 1952 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Seri: by F.C. Roberts and Woolsey. 1931 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Seri: by Gilbert Sykes. ca. 1930s (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Seri: by Mrs. Juan Harrington Xavier and Julian Hayden. 1940-1941 (Box 27, Folder 3-4)
    - Seri book (proposed) using 478 color slides. 1974 (Box 27, Folder 5-6)
    - William Neil Smith. (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - W. N. Smith with Seris: by G.M. Daetz. 1960 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - W. N. Smith - house at Desemboque. April 1965 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Stick game. ca. 1950 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Tecomate, Tiburon Island: by Bernice E. Brand. 1949 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Tiburon Island and Desemboque: by W. N. Smith (negatives). Summer-Fall 1947 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Trip to Arizona with William Neil Smith. ca. 1952 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Trip to San Esteban Island - traveling by ponga from Punta La Cruz to the middle of Infiernillo Straits following Tiburon Island shore. September 15-25, 1947 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Trip to San Esteban Island - leaving San Esteban and landing at "Gyah-hoe," south coast, Tiburon Island. September 1947 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Trip to San Esteban Island - roasting mescal heads at "Gyah-hoe," south coast, Tiburon Is. September 1947 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Trip to San Esteban, Tiburon - Sausal, Punta de la Luz, Tineja Cave sites, deer. 1947 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Trip to Tiburon Island, mouth of Arroyo Gyah-hac south coast - also Hactoe, Pozo Caracol and "Andesh-ee-oh-tumm" [Seri groups with Montaño Family]. October-November 1947 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Trip inland from Infiernillo coast at "Hactoe," Pozo Caracol and "Andesh-ee-ah-tumm," Tiburon Island. October-November 1947 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Trip in rubber raft from Tiburon Island to Bahia Sarjento on Sonora coast. November 1947 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Trip from Tucson to Desemboque by way of Hermosillo; Seri scenes at Desemboque. 1947 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Trip to United States by four Seri men, sponsored by Quakers. Fall 1950 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous photographs. (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Negatives and contact prints of photographs by William Neil Smith - 22 rolls of film; one sleeve, Desemboque; one folder of miscellaneous negatives (The contact sheets made by Doug Bullock in 1996). 1947-1952 (Box 29)
    - Contains contact sheets made from negatives in Box 29, and prints from other folders with extensive annotations made by William N. Smith. Photographs cover a four month period from September-December 1947, when Mr. Smith was traveling with a Seri family,(Montano) on their fall daily round on the mainland and out to Tiburon Island. 1996-1997 (Box 29A-29B)
    - Negatives of photographs by Hugh Holub -- Seri ironwood carvings. ca. 1947-1955 (Box 30)
  - Color Slides
    - Slide box 1. (Box 31)
      Includes the following:
      Sunsets.
      Marine desert environment: Geography & flora; camps; people; boats.
      Use of environment: Ach-aach; turtle hunting; gathering activities; winter hunting camps/hunting inland.
      Cultural Life: children & their activities; personal adornment - hair braiding/face painting, religion.
      Crafts: pottery, basketry, balsa boat manufacture.
      Acculturation: Desemboque, Seri-Mexican fish economy.
      Addenda
    - Slide box 2. 1945-1947 (Box 31)
      Puerto Kino, Buenos Aires Ranch, Desemboque. December 1945-January 1946
      Tiburon Island. January 1946
      Desemboque, Sonora. June-July 1946
      Tiburon Island. July-August 1946
      Desemboque, Sonora. August 1946
      Desemboque, Sonora. October 1946-January 1947
      Tucson, Ariz.-Desemboque, Sonora. June-July 1947
      Desemboque, Sonora. July 1947
    - Slide box 3. 1947-1949 (Box 31)
      Tiburon Island trip. August 1947
      Desemboque. August-September 1947
      San Esteban Island trip. September 15-25, 1947
      Tiburon Island. September-November 1947
      Campo Dollar. February 1948
      Desemboque and Isla Patos. August-September 1948
      Tiburon Island trip. September 1948
      Seri trip to U.S.A. September-October 1948
      Desemboque/Tiburon Island? ca. 1948
      Trip inland, Tiburon Island. November 1948-January 1949
    - Slide box 4. 1949-1950 (Box 31)
      Miscellaneous [unmounted]. ca. 1949?
      Seri maps, baskets and santos -- Tucson. May 1949
      Desemboque. June and December 1949
      San Esteban Island trip. June 1949
      Desemboque. June 1949
      Tecomate camp (Ach-aach), Tiburon Island. July-October 1949
      Desemboque. November 1949
      Desemboque -- Lynd Warren duplicates. November 1949
      Desemboque. November-December 1949
      Winter camp, Infiernillo Strait, Tiburon Island. 1950
      Tiburon Island. June-July 1950
      Tecomate camp, Tiburon Island. August-September 1950
      Seri trip to U.S.A. September-October 1950
      Desemboque. October-December 1950
    - Slide box 5. 1951-1956 (Box 32)
      Campo Dollar. January 1951
      Winter camp, Infiernillo Strait, Tiburon Island. January 1951
      Sonora Desert. March 1951
      Tecomate camp, Tiburon Island. June 1951
      Air views: Punta Antiguilla, Bahia Kino. June 1951
      Tecomate camp, Tiburon Island. August-September 1951
      Seri trip to U.S.A. September-November 1951
      Mazatlan-La Paz trip. January-February 1952
      Guaymas, Sonora & Hermosillo. February 1952
      Air views: Tiburon Island area. June 1952
      Seri trip to U.S.A. October-December 1952
      Miscellaneous. December 1952-June 1953
      Tiburon Island. ca. 1954
      Seri measles epidemic, Tiburon Island landing strip. April 1955
      Air views: Tiburon Island, Desemboque. March 1956
    - Slide box 6. 1960-1969 (Box 32)
      Maps, October 1960; Baskets, by David Brugge ca. 1965
      Tiburon Island, Punta Chueca. February-March 1965
      Desemboque, Sonora & Tucson, Ariz. April-November 1965
      Desemboque, Patos Island, Pond Island, Angel de la Guarda Island. April-May 1966
      Patos Island trip: Los Angeles Bay, Isla Partida, Isla Raza, Isla Salsipuedes, Isla San Lorenzo. May 1966
      Punta Chueca, [noted: "last roll of Seri Kodachromes]. May 1966
      Patos Island trip: Bahia de Los Angeles. 1966
      Seri trip with Conrad Bahre. March-April 1966
      Muleje, Baja Calif. (flight across Gulf of Calif. to Hermosillo). May 1966
      Ironwood carvings, baskets: by Hugh Holub. 1969
      Seri figurine study, Series I-VII. ca. 1966
      Figurines - Kino Bay area: by Claire Brey. 1967
      Shell midden prehistoric sites. No date
  - Motion Picture Film
    - Reel of 16 mm film, "Seri Workprint." (Box 33)
    - Reel of 16 mm film, "Seri Indians on Trips to Northern Arizona, (1200 feet) - original Kodachrome film, Not a duplicate." 1951, 1952 (Box 33)
    - Miscellaneous film clips. Scenes include: maps, landscapes, birds in the sky, man rowing, and people. ca. 1956 (Box 33)
    - 12-1/2 inch reels of 16 mm. film. 1950-1956 (Box 34)
      Seri film - reel II - duplicate work print - various scenes. 1950-1956
      Seri film - reel IV - duplicate work print - various scenes, youth at Tiburon, Seri youth at Grand Canyon and Ach-aach. 1950-1953
      Seri film -- Viking duplicate -- mostly Tecomate. Summer 1951 and 1952
    - 7 inch reels of 16 mm. film. 1950-1960s (Box 34)
      Seri trip to the States. Fall 1950
      Cut of Seri movies of trips to States. 1950-1952
      Seri film - reel V (incomplete) - duplicate work print. No date
      San Fernando Valley State College-E. Carpenter Project -- duplicate of all map sequences from original Seri film project - work print duplicate. 1960s
      San Fernando Valley State College -- Carpenter Project -- work print duplicate - shots from Kodachrome stills loaned for film project. 1960s
    - 3 inch and 3 1/2 inch reels of 16 mm. film. 1955-1960s (Box 34)
      Ed Carpenter's Project Fiasco. 1960s
      Seri Indians - Tecomate cuts - original film. No date
      Maps of Seri Area cuts - 3 reels in boxes labeled I, II, III. No date
      Seri Measles Epidemic Aid -- 2 reels in boxes. Spring 1955
      Cuts from original film -- Seri Trips to States (?) or sea turtle feast. No date
      Pieces of movie film for Seris. No date
  - Sound Recordings
    The condition of the tapes is very poor. Please consult with a librarian before requesting access.
    - Seri recording -- 7 inch reels of tape. 1950-1958 (Box 35)
      Seri violin and linguistics (labeled "Reel #1")(Ned Spicer's house-Tucson). October 9, 1950
      Seri violin and linguistics (labeled "Reel #2")(Ned Spicer's house, Tucson). October 25, 1950
      Seri linguistics (word lists) -- (labeled "Reel #3")(Ned Spicer's house-Tucson). October 25, 1950
      Seri linguistics (word lists): sky, water, sea, land terms (labeled "Reel #4"). October 30, 1951
      Seri word lists: land terms, land animals, fire terms -- (labeled "Reel #5"), (UA Anthropology Department, Tucson). October 31, 1950
      Seri word lists: kinship terms -- (labeled "Reel #6"), (Ned Spicer's house, Tucson). October 31, 1950
      Seri word lists and sentences: colors, colors in combination, coffee drinking, raining, plurals -- (labeled "Reel #7"). November 3, 1951
      Seri word lists: plurals -- Jose Angel Montano -- (labeled "Reel #8"), (Ned Spicer's house, Tucson). November 3, 1951
      Seri music, words (side I only) (labeled "Reel #9-A") [side II: Cantonese counting and kinship terms]. November 3, 1951
      Seri word lists: material culture -- (labeled "Reel #9-B"), (UA Anthropology Department, Tucson). November 7, 1950
      Southwest and Seri Indian songs: side I: Southwest songs, (recorded by Odd Halsete; Pueblo Grande, Phoenix); track 1) Apache, 2) Pima, 3) Jemez, 4) Hopi, 5) Cochiti, 6) Walapai. 1958 side II: Seri harmonica, violin and songs (recorded by W.H.S.). Jose Montano (Halone) harmonica solo, Jose Juan Moreno (Hutt) violin and song. (Tucson, 1950-1951). Fall 1950
      Soundtrack from "Disneyland" program, "Peoples and Places." October 1955
      Seri Puberty Fiesta for Lidia Ibarra, Desemboque, (4 reels)(songs and foot drums). June 11, 1958
    - Seri recordings -- 5 inch reels of tape. 1956-1964 (Box 35)
      Seri conversation and joking, Punta Chueca, (songs and foot drums). August-September 1956
      Archivo de Folklore - INBA: Huichal music, songs for peyote festival, holy week, etc. -- (gift from Mexico City). May 4, 1964
    - Other Native and Spanish recordings -- 7 inch reels. (Box 35)
      Native music of North and South America and of West Africa, including Hopi war chant, Upper Amazon tribes (Iawa, Bora), and West African tribes (Cacule, Malinke). December 1957 - January 1958